Guide to the Richard Erdoes Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Photographic Materials, 1952-1999; Series III; 62.25; (70 boxes)
  - Slides
    - "Sioux Ceremonies 2, Cheyennes"
      - "Peyote Paraphernalia Painting", 1970, undated; 24 slides (Box 75)
      - "Peyote in Tent 1975", 1975-1983, undated; 24 slides (Box 75)
      - "1977 Sundance Tent. Cooking Apache Tent", 27 slides (Box 75)
      - "Dick Foolbull Flutes", 1974-1988, undated; 24 slides (Box 75)
      - "Leonard Double Exposure", 1976-1993; 33 slides (Box 75)
      - "Leonard Double Exposure", 1976, undated; 27 slides (Box 75)
      - "Rachel", 1972-1975, undated; 14 slides (Box 75)
      - "Archie Fire Lame Deer Sweat", 1988-1993; 20 slides (Box 75)
      - "Archie Sweat", 1988; 21 slides (Box 75)
      - "Leonard NY Pipe Ceremony", 1971; 10 slides (Box 75)
      - "Lame Deer Montana", undated; 34 slides (Box 75)
      - "Mama Strange Owl Meat Cutting", undated; 19 slides (Box 75)
      - "Rachel Strange Owl", undated; 20 slides (Box 75)
      - "Rachel & Corn", undated; 19 slides (Box 75)
      - "Cheyenne Children Powwow Drums", undated; 16 slides (Box 75)
      - "Cheyenne Children Women Baby", undated; 28 slides (Box 75)
      - "Cheyenne Res.", 1972, undated; 31 slides (Box 76)
      - "Cheyenne Crow Graves", undated; 18 slides (Box 76)
    - "Ireland, Amsterdam"
      - "Shore Ports", 1965-1991, undated; 24 slides (Box 76)
      - "Cashel", 1983-1991, undated; 19 slides (Box 76)
      - "Cashel Kruger", 1983-1991, undated; 25 slides (Box 76)
      - "Dublin", undated; 15 slides (Box 76)
      - "Boats Ships Marine Life", 1966-1991, undated; 18 slides (Box 76)
      - "People", 1985-1991, undated; 17 slides (Box 76)
      - "Irish People", 1983-1985, undated; 17 slides (Box 76)
      - "Irish People", 1985-1991, undated; 19 slides (Box 76)
      - "Irish Antiquity Abbeys", 1984-1991, undated; 19 slides (Box 76)
      - "Killarney Gap of Dunlow Muckross", 1991, undated; 24 slides (Box 76)
      - "Donkey Race", undated; 26 slides (Box 76)
      - "Aran Islands", undated; 20 slides (Box 76)
      - "Brigid Maloney Grattan Freier", 1985, undated; 12 slides (Box 76)
      - "Irish Landscape", 1985-1991, undated; 23 slides (Box 76)
      - "Irish Farms / Keats", 1985-1991, undated; 27 slides (Box 76)
      - "Kells Tara High Crosses", 1985, undated; 24 slides (Box 76)
      - "Caravan Tinkers Pub", 1991, undated; 17 slides (Box 76)
      - "Ogham Stone Drumlechs Etc.", 1985-1991, undated; 9 slides (Box 76)
      - "Prehistory Museum", 1991, undated; 10 slides (Box 76)
      - "Birds Sea Shells", undated; 26 slides (Box 76)
      - "Amsterdam", undated; 22 slides (Box 76)
      - "Houses Towns", 1985-1991, undated; 22 slides (Box 76)
      - "Dromoland Bunratty Yeats, Westport", 1984-1994, undated; 15 slides (Box 76)
      - "Clonfert", 1985-1991; 8 slides (Box 76)
    - "Western History, White"
      - "Landrush Posters", 1967-1985, undated; 27 slides (Box 76)
      - "Wagon Trains", 1975-1976, undated; 40 slides (Box 76)
      - "Settlers Farms", 1976-1986, undated; 37 slides (Box 76)
      - "Western Scenes", 1976-1985, undated; 38 slides (Box 76)
      - "Circus Military", 1975-1976, undated; 40 slides (Box 77)
      - "Cowboys", 1976-1986, undated; 29 slides (Box 77)
      - "Saloons Gambling", 1976, undated; 27 slides (Box 77)
      - "Towns Settlements Stores", 1975-1976, undated; 33 slides (Box 77)
      - "Boats", 1976, undated; 25 slides (Box 77)
      - "Hunters Non-Buffalo", 1976, undated; 33 slides (Box 77)
      - "Buffalo Beaver", 1970-1980, undated; 37 slides (Box 77)
      - "Hunters, Trappers", 1970-1980, undated; 42 slides (Box 77)
      - "Sheep, Chinese Mining Disasters, Strikes, [Sheepwar(?)]", 1976; 24 slides (Box 77)
      - "Portraits", 1970-1992, undated; 30 slides (Box 77)
      - "Persons Portraits", 1976; 41 slides (Box 77)
      - "Women Female Bandits", 1970-1976; 34 slides (Box 77)
      - "Floods Fires", 1976; 24 slides (Box 77)
      - "Transports", 1975-1986; 20 slides (Box 77)
      - "Railroads", 1975-1976, undated; 35 slides (Box 77)
      - "Explorers Lewis & Clark Fremont", 1973-1976, undated; 29 slides (Box 77)
      - "Calamity Little Britches Mme Moustache Poker Alice", 1976; 23 slides (Box 77)
      - "Bad Men Shootings Mayhem", 1976, undated; 35 slides (Box 77)
      - "Bad Men", 1976-1984, undated; 35 slides (Box 77)
      - "Miners", 1970-1976, undated; 37 slides (Box 77)
    - "Florida, Long Boat Key, New Orleans"
      - "Shells, Beach, Ocean", 1973, undated; 78 slides (Box 77)
      - "Sky Sunsets", 1973-1980, undated; 75 slides (Box 77)
      - "Wading Birds", 1973, undated; 72 slides (Box 78)
      - "Birds Wading", 1973, undated; 64 slides (Box 78)
      - "New Orleans, Jackson Square", 1973, undated; 56 slides (Box 78)
      - "Bayou Ecology", undated; 64 slides (Box 78)
      - "New Orleans Medium", 1973, undated; 62 slides (Box 78)
      - "Vieux Carre Long", 1973, undated; 61 slides (Box 78)
      - "Vieux Carre Extreme Close Up", 1973, undated; 30 slides (Box 78)
      - "New Orleans Medium Close Up", 1973, undated; 56 slides (Box 78)
      - "Longboat Key", 1969-1985, undated; 64 slides (Box 78)
      - "New Orleans Misc.", 1973, undated; 37 slides (Box 78)
    - "New Mexico Nature, Fall, Winter, Chama, etc."
      - "Fall Colors Medium, Close Up", 1977-1992; 29 slides (Box 78)
      - "Fall Colors Medium", 1977-1990, undated; 32 slides (Box 78)
      - "Fall Colors Long", 1977-1989; 30 slides (Box 78)
      - "Fall Colors Extreme Long", 1977-1987, undated; 24 slides (Box 78)
      - "Fall Colors Pecos, Cienega, Etc.", 1977-1982, undated; 24 slides (Box 78)
      - "Leaves, Leaves On Ground", 1974-1981, undated; 23 slides (Box 78)
      - "Black and Orange Forest Patterns", 1977-1978, undated; 23 slides (Box 78)
      - "Fall Colors Close Up", 1977-1989, undated; 29 slides (Box 78)
      - "Winter Medium Close Up", 1983-1989, undated; 24 slides (Box 78)
      - "Winter Medium Long", 1977-1983, undated; 29 slides (Box 79)
      - "Winter Santa Fe Mountains Long", 1977-1987, undated; 28 slides (Box 79)
      - "Fall Colors Chama", 1977-1982, undated; 22 slides (Box 79)
      - "Waterfalls", 1975-1987, undated; 32 slides (Box 79)
      - "Brazos and Brook", 1981-1992, undated; 15 slides (Box 79)
      - "Winter, New Mexico, Not Santa Fe Mountains", 1977-1985, undated; 20 slides (Box 79)
      - "Winter, Close Up", 1982-1989, undated; 18 slides (Box 79)
      - "Chama River Erosions", 1975-1981, undated; 24 slides (Box 79)
      - "Rio Grande Gorge Crosses", 1972-1984, undated; 32 slides (Box 79)
      - "Jemez Mountains, Jemez Canyon", 1975-1985, undated; 36 slides (Box 79)
      - "Gila Scape Jemez So. DA Springs Havasu", 1967-1989, undated; 32 slides (Box 79)
      - "Mimbres, Giga Mts, Fog, Mist, Etc. Hermit Peaks", 1977-1989, undated; 21 slides (Box 79)
      - "Crestone, Colo Mountains", 1980-1991, undated; 26 slides (Box 79)
      - "N.M. Landscape", 1972-1985, undated; 34 slides (Box 79)
      - "N.M. Landscape", 1974-1982, undated; 29 slides (Box 79)
    - "Everglades 1973"
      - "Vegetation", 1973-1975, undated; 34 slides (Box 79)
      - "Mangroves", 1973, undated; 24 slides (Box 79)
      - "Everglades Palms, Trees", 1965-1969, undated; 24 slides (Box 79)
      - "Tamiami Wetland", 1974, undated; 23 slides (Box 79)
      - "[Gulls]", 1973, undated; 37 slides (Box 79)
      - "Gator Close Up", 1973, undated; 28 slides (Box 79)
      - "Alligator", 1973, undated; 34 slides (Box 79)
      - "Cyprus [Egr?], Swamps, Moss", 1973, undated; 24 slides (Box 79)
      - "Ibis Stork", undated; 32 slides (Box 79)
      - "Anhinga Close Up", 1973, undated; 8 slides (Box 79)
      - "Anhinga Long", 1973, undated; 36 slides (Box 79)
      - "Woodpecker Bittern Gallinule", 1973, undated; 30 slides (Box 80)
      - "Spider, Butterfly", undated; 16 slides (Box 80)
      - "Cormoray, Ducks", 1973, undated; 21 slides (Box 80)
      - "Egret Close Up Medium", 1973, undated; 24 slides (Box 80)
      - "Egret Long", 1973, undated; 35 slides (Box 80)
      - "Buzzard", 1973, undated; 19 slides (Box 80)
      - "Snails, Seashells", undated; 16 slides (Box 80)
      - "Pelican B", undated; 27 slides (Box 80)
      - "Pelican A", undated; 27 slides (Box 80)
      - "Blue Heron", 1973, undated; 20 slides (Box 80)
      - "Flight Sunset", undated; 30 slides (Box 80)
      - "Mass Flight, Medium", undated; 20 slides (Box 80)
      - "Odd Birds", undated; 31 slides (Box 80)
    - "Bottle House Golden, NM"
      - "A house with glass bottles in sculptures and architecture", 1983-1984, undated; 38 slides (Box 80)
    - "Indian Market Santa Fe"
      - "Scenes from a market", 1975-1982; 35 slides (Box 81)
    - "Balloons Yale"
      - "Slides of Hot Air Balloons", 1978-1984; 53 slides (Box 81)
    - "Arizona 1985, N.M. Towns, Balloons"
      - "Puerto Rico Art", 1984, undated; 41 slides (Box 81)
      - "El Paso", 1984; 27 slides (Box 81)
      - "Grand Canyon, Some Balloon", 1986, undated; 15 slides (Box 81)
      - "Balloons", 1978-1984.; 70 slides (Box 81)
      - "Puerto Rico", 1983-1984, undated; 34 slides (Box 81)
      - "Madrid N. M.", 1975-1991; 29 slides (Box 81)
      - "Arizona Landscape", 1975-1994, undated; 54 slides (Box 81)
      - "Las Vegas", 1982; 24 slides (Box 81)
      - "Architecture Colorado S.D. Arizona, Etc.", 1975-1985, undated; 19 slides (Box 81)
      - "Tucson, Havasupai", 1975-1985, undated; 43 slides (Box 81)
      - "Tumacacori Tubac Tumacacori", 1984-1985, undated; 34 slides (Box 81)
      - "Tombstone AZ", 1980-1985, undated; 30 slides (Box 81)
      - "Georgetown Crestone Colorado Towns", 1972-1985, undated; 82 slides (Box 81)
      - "San Xavier Interior", 1984-1985, undated; 23 slides (Box 81)
      - "San Xavier Exterior", 1985; 39 slides (Box 81)
      - "Mexican art", 1975-1984, undated; 60 slides (Box 81)
      - "Mexican art", 1975-1984, undated; 21 slides (Box 81)
      - "Spanish Colonial Art", 1963-1985, undated; 19 slides (Box 81)
    - "New England, Westport, Water birds, Boston, Marine Life, VT, Maine, Bar Harbor, Etc."
      - "Ed's Place view from his window", 1971-1980, undated; 30 slides (Box 81)
      - "Waterbirds on Mill Pond", 1969-1980, undated; 28 slides (Box 81)
      - "Westport Connecticut Mill Pond, Sherwin Island", 1971-1980, undated; 40 slides (Box 81)
      - "N.Y.- CT Seashore", 1969-1975, undated; 33 slides (Box 81)
      - "Westport Shore", 1976, undated; 27 slides (Box 82)
      - "Canada Geese, Swans", 1971-1976, undated; 30 slides (Box 82)
      - "Canada Geese", 1971-1976, undated; 36 slides (Box 82)
      - "Ed Sammi's Canoe with Bird", 1980; 21 slides (Box 82)
      - "Boston", 1976, undated; 23 slides (Box 82)
      - "Westport Marine Life", 1968-1977, undated; 30 slides (Box 82)
      - "Westport Marine Life Maine too", 1974, undated; 30 slides (Box 82)
      - "Westport Marine Life", 1976-1978, undated; 26 slides (Box 82)
      - "New Hampshire Akwesasne Fog", 1975-1976, undated; 23 slides (Box 82)
      - "Salem Museum", 1963-1982, undated; 16 slides (Box 82)
      - "Massachusetts", 1963-1977, undated; 37 slides (Box 82)
      - "U.S.S. Constitution", undated; 33 slides (Box 82)
      - "Wiscasset Maine", 1976-1988; 23 slides (Box 82)
      - "Maine Coast", 1968-1978, undated; 34 slides (Box 82)
      - "Manchester Gravestones, Marble Quarry", 1968, undated; 34 slides (Box 82)
      - "Vermont", 1974, undated; 18 slides (Box 82)
      - "Maine Winter", 1977-1986; 19 slides (Box 82)
      - "Maine Woods Beaver Pond", 1968-1986; 38 slides (Box 82)
      - "Mt. Desert Island", 1968-1988; 39 slides (Box 82)
      - "Bar Harbor Cove", 1977-1988, undated; 35 slides (Box 82)
    - "Trip East 1988 Also Amish, Ticonderoga + D.C. Newcastle, San Gennaro"
      - "Penn Delaware Canal", 1968-1987, undated; 20 slides (Box 82)
      - "Trade Center Museum", 1976-1991; 39 slides (Box 82)
      - "Washington D.C.", 1975-1985, undated; 21 slides (Box 82)
      - "Aerials East", 1975-1988, undated; 24 slides (Box 82)
      - "Oddities NYC", 1979-1988; 26 slides (Box 82)
      - "Empire State Building", 1988; 34 slides (Box 82)
      - "San Gennaro", 1988; 13 slides (Box 83)
      - "Riverside Park", 1984-1986; 13 slides (Box 83)
      - "NYC Architecture", 1982-1990; 35 slides (Box 83)
      - "Lower East Side", 1985-1988, undated; 20 slides (Box 83)
      - "Our Old NYC Neighborhood", 1984-1987, undated; 38 slides (Box 83)
      - "Ticonderoga Russian Church", 1968, undated; 31 slides (Box 83)
      - "Upstate NY Philipse Manor", 1974-1988, undated; 37 slides (Box 83)
      - "Harpers Ferry", 1975, undated; 33 slides (Box 83)
      - "Pine Bush Shawagunks", 1982-1988; 28 slides (Box 83)
      - "NYC / Chicago Misc.", 1971-1988, undated; 32 slides (Box 83)
      - "Maine, Shops, Houses", 1975-1988, undated; 29 slides (Box 83)
      - "Amish", 1975-1987; 17 slides (Box 83)
      - "Amish", 1975-1986, undated; 31 slides (Box 83)
      - "Newcastle", 1975-1978, undated; 22 slides (Box 83)
      - "Newcastle Delaware", 1975-1978, undated; 28 slides (Box 83)
      - "Fall Colors Maine", 1975-1988, undated; 40 slides (Box 83)
      - "Upper West Side 89th Street", 1982-1992, undated; 23 slides (Box 83)
    - "New Mexico Towns, Silverado, Young Guns, Farelitos"
      - "Mexico, Palenque", 1980, undated; 16 slides (Box 83)
      - "Mosque Albuquerque NM", 1977-1991; 42 slides (Box 83)
      - "Old NY 1950s", 1970-1991, undated; 9 slides (Box 83)
      - "Plains Indians", 1970-1999, undated; 16 slides (Box 83)
      - "Farms Villages", 1975-1991; 26 slides (Box 83)
      - "Frijoles Falls Bandelier", 1983-1989, undated; 21 slides (Box 83)
      - "Amphitheater, Natural", 1975-1988; 27 slides (Box 83)
      - "Albuquerque", 1975-1988; 24 slides (Box 83)
      - "Ojo Caliente 1989", 33 slides (Box 83)
      - "Maya Art", 1980-1991; 11 slides (Box 83)
      - "Young Guns", 1988; 35 slides (Box 83)
      - "Young Guns", 1988; 35 slides (Box 84)
      - "Forest Fires", 1980-1984, undated; 12 slides (Box 84)
      - "Rio Grande Rafts Gorge", 1987-1989; 29 slides (Box 84)
      - "Bernalillo", 1984, undated; 14 slides (Box 84)
      - "Pet Parade", 1985; 42 slides (Box 84)
      - "Inn of Loretto Faralitos", 1988; 13 slides (Box 84)
      - "Fort Union", 1987; 33 slides (Box 84)
      - "Fort Union", 1987-1989; 25 slides (Box 84)
      - "N.M. Nature landscapes - Large vistas", 1975-1997; 25 slides (Box 84)
      - "Miscellaneous Oddities", 1975-1992, undated; 39 slides (Box 84)
      - "New Mexico Towns", 1975-1990, undated; 38 slides (Box 84)
      - "Winter Forest Fires", 1977-1992; 27 slides (Box 84)
      - "Ocate Cuba Courthouse", 1987-1991; 37 slides (Box 84)
    - "Large Western U.S. Animals, Santa Fe Architecture, Fiesta, Etc."
      - "Buffalo Close Up", 1971-1991, undated; 33 slides (Box 84)
      - "Buffalo Medium", 1986-1991, undated; 38 slides (Box 84)
      - "Buffalo Close Up", 1971-1991, undated; 35 slides (Box 84)
      - "Buffalo Long", 1971-1972, undated; 33 slides (Box 84)
      - "Butterflies Dragonflies Bugs", 1979-1995, undated; 26 slides (Box 84)
      - "Moose Mountain Sheep", 1979-1985, undated; 31 slides (Box 84)
      - "Buffalo Resting Rolling", 1966-1986, undated; 20 slides (Box 84)
      - "Buffalo In Winter Calves", 1980-1991, undated; 23 slides (Box 84)
      - "Antelope C.O.", 1986-1994, undated; 17 slides (Box 84)
      - "Antelope Long", 1980-1986, undated; 25 slides (Box 84)
      - "Deer, Mule Deer", 1980-1987, undated; 31 slides (Box 84)
      - "Elk, Moose, Mountain Sheep", 1970-1985, undated; 33 slides (Box 84)
      - "Santa Fe Doorways", 1977-1992, undated; 37 slides (Box 84)
      - "Doorways", 1977-1992, undated; 33 slides (Box 84)
      - "Lizards, Reptiles, Insects", 1974-1992, undated; 34 slides (Box 85)
      - "Squirrel, Marmots, Longhorn", 1966-1992, undated; 32 slides (Box 85)
      - "Fiesta Riders", 1975-1988, undated; 33 slides (Box 85)
      - "Santa Fe Murals", 1970-1992, undated; 28 slides (Box 85)
      - "Santa Fe Murals", 1975-1992, undated; 37 slides (Box 85)
      - "Santa Fe Adobe Houses", 1975-1992, undated; 41 slides (Box 85)
      - "Santa Fe Fiesta", 1963-1998, undated; 32 slides (Box 85)
      - "Fiesta", 1975-1988; 26 slides (Box 85)
      - "Windows Fences Ristras", 1975-1992, undated; 33 slides (Box 85)
      - "NM Towns", 1979-1997, undated; 25 slides (Box 85)
    - "New Mexico Nature, Flora"
      - "N.M. Arizona Dams, Canals", 1975-1990, undated; 19 slides (Box 85)
      - "N.M. Reservoirs Streams, Ponds, Etc.", 1975-1990, undated; 33 slides (Box 85)
      - "Rock Formations Rocks, Stones", 1975-1988, undated; 35 slides (Box 85)
      - "Great Sand Dunes, City of Rocks", 1974-1987, undated; 22 slides (Box 85)
      - "Forest Scenes, Leaves, Needles", 1972-1992, undated; 33 slides (Box 85)
      - "Branches, Trunks", 1968-1992, undated; 33 slides (Box 85)
      - "Trees", 1977-1992; 31 slides (Box 85)
      - "Mimbres River Crestone Brook", 1981-1987, undated; 16 slides (Box 85)
      - "Mushrooms, Toadstools, Moss, Jimson Weed", 1966-1992, undated; 24 slides (Box 85)
      - "Grasses, Horsetails Reeds", 1972-1991, undated; 34 slides (Box 85)
      - "Shrubs", 1975-1989, undated; 36 slides (Box 85)
      - "Buds, Blossoms", 1975-1985, undated; 25 slides (Box 85)
      - "More Wildflowers", 1975-1992, undated; 26 slides (Box 85)
      - "Wildflowers, General", 1975-1992, undated; 39 slides (Box 85)
      - "Wildflowers, Yellow", 1972-1992, undated; 39 slides (Box 86)
      - "Wildflowers, Indian Paintbrush, Red Flowers", 1981-1987, undated; 28 slides (Box 86)
      - "Lichens", 1972-1987, undated; 23 slides (Box 86)
      - "Arizona Cacti Saguaro", 1985, undated; 14 slides (Box 86)
      - "Cacti General", 1966-1989, undated; 26 slides (Box 86)
      - "Yucca Pincushion", 1978-1987, undated; 17 slides (Box 86)
      - "Succulents Cholla", 1972-1994; 30 slides (Box 86)
      - "Sunsets", 1975-1984, undated; 27 slides (Box 86)
      - "Sky Dusk", 1973-1988, undated; 24 slides (Box 86)
      - "Sky Rainbow", 1973-1992, undated; 24 slides (Box 86)
    - "South Dakota: Badlands, Black Hills, Forts, Saloons, Landscapes, Etc."
      - "S.D. Badlands, Extreme Long", 1972-1988, undated; 29 slides (Box 86)
      - "Toadstool Park, 1972", 1966-1986, undated; 28 slides (Box 86)
      - "Toadstool Park, 1967", 1972-1991, undated; 33 slides (Box 86)
      - "Iowa, South Dakota, Farms, Ranches", 1971-1991, undated; 30 slides (Box 86)
      - "Badlands, Close Up", 1972-1986, undated; 26 slides (Box 86)
      - "Badlands, Medium, Close Up", 1986-1988, undated; 32 slides (Box 86)
      - "Badlands, Medium", 1972-1986, undated; 34 slides (Box 86)
      - "Badlands, Long", 1962-1986, undated; 32 slides (Box 86)
      - "Black Hills, Needles", 1971-1991, undated; 32 slides (Box 86)
      - "Fossil Creek", 1970-1988, undated; 25 slides (Box 86)
      - "Badlands Sunset", 1962-1988, undated; 28 slides (Box 86)
      - "Badlands, Grasses, Yucca", 1972-1986, undated; 35 slides (Box 86)
      - "Black Hills Winter", undated; 31 slides (Box 86)
      - "Black Hills Fall", 1962-1986, undated; 34 slides (Box 86)
      - "Mt. Rushmore", 1977-1993, undated; 27 slides (Box 86)
      - "Sylvan Lake, Stockade Lake, Missouri River", 1971-1993, undated; 39 slides (Box 86)
      - "Black Hills Plants, Flowers", 1966-1977, undated; 36 slides (Box 87)
      - "Black Hills Plants", 1975-1991, undated; 27 slides (Box 87)
      - "South Dakota Landscape", 1975-1986, undated; 31 slides (Box 87)
      - "Black Hills General Rockchuck Falls", 1971-1986, undated; 36 slides (Box 87)
      - "S.D. Saloons Hotels", 1970-1986, undated; 31 slides (Box 87)
      - "Saloons General", 1975-1986, undated; 33 slides (Box 87)
      - "Saloons Denver Wall Drug", 1975-1998, undated; 27 slides (Box 87)
      - "Fts. Chadron Robinson + Laramie", 1980-1991, undated; 37 slides (Box 87)
    - Unmounted Slides, circa 1970-1990, undated; Approximately 20 slides (Box 87)
      Unmounted slides are arranged in the order they were removed from existing slide sets. Each unmounted slide is labeled with its original set name in order to preserve provenance.
  - Photographic Prints
    In this subseries, dated material is listed first in chronological order. Undated work is then arranged alphabetically based on Erdoes's labeling.
    This subseries consists of 524 photographic prints on paper and board and two photographic collages. Color images are present, but the majority of the images are black and white. Some of the prints are annotated by Erdoes, and bear captions on their verso. Photographs in "Acoma; Odd Photos and Historical" (box 92) appear to have been prepared for exhibition. Other photographs in this subseries bear publication markings or further printing instructions; a number of the images are photographs that Erdoes used in his books and in other publications.
    The photographs primarily reflect Erdoes's interest in American Indians, and appear to be a collection of favored images from his vast photographic holdings. There is likely some overlap between the images present in this subseries, and the negatives, transparencies, and slides present elsewhere in Series III. Erdoes used broad categories to describe the sets he compiled, and some images appear in more than one labeled grouping.
    In addition to sets of images documenting Navajo (Diné), Lakota and Pueblo communities during the latter half of the twentieth century, there are sets of images showcasing Erdoes's commercial photography, including nearly a dozen images of workers and oil rigs in Wilson Creek, Colorado (box 93); a selection of prints documenting the streets of New York City and the landscapes of rural New England and Nebraska (box 95); and a cache of prints documenting Erdoes's trip to the West Indies (box 96)
    - "Sioux, People, Faces, Scenes" (139 color and black and white prints), 1955-1993,undated (Box 88, Folder 388-393)
      Alternate Erdoes title: "Contents: Civil Rights, Wounded Knee, Sioux Rites, Sun Dance, Pueblos, Navajos, Petroglyphs"
      Includes portraits of the Crow Dog family and other Lakota tribal members, as well as images from the 1973 occupation of Wounded Knee, and the filming of the 1993 film, Lakota Woman. Images of Hopi, Navajo, and Pueblo individuals and community gatherings are also present. Two photographs are attributed to Cy Griffin and Erich Erdoes.
    - "Navajo and Pueblo, Prehistory, Plains, West, 1961 and 1962" (39 black and white prints), 1961-1962, undated (Box 89)
    - "Plains Indians" (84 black and white prints and 2 photographic collages), 1964-1971,undated; Includes images of Leonard Crow Dog, Henry Crow Dog, and other Lakota individuals, as well as images of Crow, Arapaho, and Arikara people and gatherings. (Box 90)
    - "Acoma; Odd Photos and Historical" (54 black and white prints), undated (Box 92)
      Includes photographs of Acoma, New Mexico; the Antonia family; Pueblo communities and events; and Navajo (Diné) people
    - Oil Rigs (11 black and white prints), undated (Box 93)
    - "Southwest Indians, Navajo, Color" (50 color prints), undated (Box 94, Folder 394-399)
    - "U.S. Northeast" (55 black and white prints), undated (Box 95)
    - "West Indies, Kids Art and Stories" (92 black and white prints), undated (Box 96)
- Films, [circa 1970]; Series IV; 0.83; (2 boxes)
  Series IV. Films is arranged chronologically.